Preliminary Inventory to the Citizens Committee for a Free Cuba Records, 1962-1974.
Hoover Institution Archives
Citizens Committee for a Free Cuba Records,
1962-1974.
73092
Citizens Committee for a Free Cuba (U.S.)
58 manuscript boxes (24 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Clippings, newsletters, press releases, reports, conference papers, speeches, and printed matter, relating primarily to the political, economic, and social effects of communism in Cuba, communist subversion in Latin America, U.S. foreign policy toward Cuba, and activities of the Cuban emigré community.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Anti-communist movements.; Communism.; Communism--Latin America.; Cubans in foreign countries.; Refugees.; Cuba.; Cuba--Foreign relations--United States.; Latin America.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--Cuba.; United States--Politics and government.
Historical Note
The Citizens Committee for a Free Cuba was a group of nearly forty private citizens, including several academics, which gathered data on all aspects of the Cuban Revolution in the 1960-1974 period and published reports in an effort to influence U.S. foreign policy toward Cuba.
The collection is a rich source of testimonials from Cubans who had recently left their country. It is also a valuable source for people who are researching insurgency movements in any of the Latin American countries in that period.
Container List
* All of these treat the subject of Soviet-aided military build-up
** Published by the Citizens Committee for a Free Cuba
- Argentina (Box 1.)
- Bolivia (Box 2.)
- Brazil (Box 3.)
- Bolivia (Box 4.)
- Columbia (Box 5-6.)
- Colombia (Box 7.)
- Costa Rica
- Cuba
  - Government
  - Cuba-West trade
- Chile (Box 8-9.)
- Dominican Republic (Box 10-11.)
- Cuban exiles (Box 12.)
  - Economy
  - Students (Box 13.)
  - Film-TV
  - 1960-1968
  - 1969-1972 (Box 14.)
  - Economic Situation
- Guatemala (Box 15.)
- Guyana (Box 16.)
- Health
  - 1962-1964
  - 1965-1972
- Haiti (Box 17.)
- Honduras
- Jamaica
- Nicaragua (Box 18.)
- Panama
- Paraguay
- Peru
- Puerto Rico
- Uruguay
- Venezuela (Box 19.)
- Argentina
- Bolivia
- Brazil
- Chile (Box 20.)
- Colombia
- Costa Rica (Box 21.)
- Dominican Republic
- Ecuador
- El Salvador
- Guatemala
- Mexico
- Cuba (Box 22.)
  - Agriculture, 1964-1967
  - Art
  - Foreign relations
    - Spain
    - China and Yugoslavia
- Mexico, 1963-1967
- Mexico (Box 23.)
- Nicaragua
- Panama
- Panama (Box 24.)
- Peru
- Peru (Box 25.)
- Cuba
  - Standard of living
    - Food
    - General (Box 26.)
  - Sugar, 1963-1972
  - Newspaper clippings, 1962 March-1963 March (Box 27.)
  - Women (Box 28.)
  - Transportation
  - Newspaper clippings, 1962 December-1963 February
- United States - Student rebellion (Box 29.)
- Cuba
  - Military build-up
  - Pinar Del Río Province*
  - Labor (Box 30.)
    - 1967-1972
    - 1964-1966
  - Indoctrination - Education
  - Industries, New
  - Isla De Pinos* (Box 31.)
  - Las Villas Province*
  - Camagüey Province*
  - Oriente Province*
  - Religion, Catholic
  - Arrival of arms
  - Havana Province*
  - Guantánamo Incidents
  - Matanzas Province*
  - Religion (Box 32.)
  - Religion, Protestant
  - Revolutionary offensive
  - Raids on Cuba
  - Sabotage
  - Shipping
- Fidel Castro speeches (Box 33.)
  - 1963-1964
  - 1967
- FREE CUBA NEWS**, Vol. 2, Nos. 1-4
- Fidel Castro speeches, 1965-1966 (Box 34.)
- FREE CUBA NEWS
  - Vol. 2, Nos 6-11
  - Vol. 3, Nos. 5-12, 14-16, 21-24
- CCFFC, Cuba Policy Research Series, Vol. 2: Cuba & U.S. Policy
- Fidel Castro speeches (Box 35.)
  - 1964
  - 1969
- Venezuela
  - 1969
  - 1965, 1967-1968 (Box 36.)
  - 1963-1964, 1966 (Box 37.)
- Uruguay, 1963-1969
- Puerto Rico (Box 38.)
  - 1963-1966, 1969-1970
  - 1967 (Box 39.)
- Argentina, 1970-1971
- Bolivia, 1970-1971
- Brazil, 1970-1971
- Chile, 1971
- Inter-American affairs (Box 40.)
- West Indies
- Mexico
- Panama, 1969
- Paraguay, 1969
- Haiti, 1969
- Peru, 1969
- Uruguay
- Venezuela, 1969
- Argentina, 1969
- Brazil, 1969
- Central America, 1969
- Bolivia, 1969 (Box 41.)
- Chile (1969)
- Colombia (1969)
- Cuba (1969)
- Dominican Republic (1969)
- Ecuador (1969)
- Tricontinental Conference - Peru Case - OAS Reaction (Box 42.)
- Tricontinental Series-AIP
- Rockefeller Report
- Cuban Cultural Congress
- Latin American Students Congress-OCLAE Activities
- Punta Del Este Conference (April 1967)
- Tricontinental Conference (Box 43.)
- Rockefeller Trip
- First Conference of Solidarity of L.A.S.O. (OLAS)
- Subversion - Latin America (Box 44.)
  - 1963-1965
  - 1966-1969
  - 1970-
- China-Latin America
- OAS (1970-)
- Cuba Guerrilla Training Camps
- U.S.-Latin America (Box 45.)
  - 1971-1972
  - 1965-1970
- Latin America - Economy
- OAS (1964-1969)
- CHE Guevara Case (Box 46.)
- Chile (1970)
- Colombia (1970-1971)
- Costa Rica (1970-1971)
- Dominican Republic (1970-1971) (Box 47.)
- Ecuador (1970-1971)
- El Salvador (1970-1971)
- Guatemala (1970-1971)
- Haiti (1970-1971)
- Honduras (1970-1971)
- Mexico (1970-1971)
- Nicaragua (1970-1971)
- Peru (1970-1971)
- Puerto Rico (1970-1971)
- Uruguay (1970-1971)
- Venezuela (1970-1971)
- General and editorials
- Newspaper clipping, Dec. 1962
- Peru (1970) (Box 48.)
- Weekly Report on Cuba
- Miscellaneous newspaper clippings
- Ardsley Saturday Morning Tape (Box 49.)
- Ardsley - What We Can Do About Cuba - Drafts
- Ardsley Conference Records
- Congressional Record (1963-1964)
- Commentaries By Paul D. Bethel, 1973-1974 (Box 50.)
- Report From Miami, USIA-Voice of America (1973-1974) (Box 51.)
- Miscellaneous OAS reports (Box 52.)
- Miscellaneous
- Chile
- Miscellaneous reports and journals (Box 53.)
- Report From Miami, USIA-Voice of America (1974)
- Miscellaneous OAS reports
- Informe Sobre Cuba (1963-1964) (Box 54.)
- Miscellaneous OAS reports
- Fidel Castro speeches (1968)
- Miscellaneous articles and clippings
- Russia-Latin America (Box 55.)
- Miscellaneous reports and journals
- Miscellaneous reports and journals (Box 56.)
- Speeches By Cuban Govt. Officials (Fidel Castro, Rául Castro, Carlos Rafael Rodrigues; 1963)
- Informe Sobre Cuba, Nos. 51-161 (Index to these is in Box 54) (Box 57.)
- Miscellaneous books
- Report on Cuban economy by Economic Research Bureau, (1968-71) (Focuses on sugar) (Box 58.)
- Alliance For Progress
- Miscellaneous books and journals